

Email: thisaremyfiles@gmail.com

Phone: +447751776483

LinkedIn: View
Portfolio: Link
GitHub: Link

## **PRFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

An Intelligent, collaborative and motivated software developer who brings a solution-driven mindset to any team using great communication, listening, and debugging skills. I have over 4 years of work experience with Java and SQL databases; 2 years+ experience with .NET, React, AWS, Azure, Kubernetes, docker, etc. I am passionate about writing clean and reusable codes, pay attention to patterns and details, and follow the DRY principle. I am calm under pressure, open to learning, and approach projects with simplicity and functionality.

### **EDUCATION**

•	MSc Software Development	
	University of Glasgow, Scotland, United Kingdom.	2021 - 2022
•	Classic Computers – Affiliated with FUTA, Akure	
	Java and SQL Development.	2016 - 2017
•	Federal University of Agriculture, Makurdi	
	Electrical and Electronics Engineering (First - Class).	2011 - 2015

### **SKILLS**

Java, React, NodeJs, ExpressJs, ASP.NET Core, Angular, JavaScript, Mobile App Development, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins CI/CD, Linux, Spring Boot, Python, Helm, Git, Azure, AWS, Kafka and RabbitMQ, Trello, HTML, CSS, XML, Bootstrap, JSON, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Computer Networking, ERP, debugging, listening, communication.

## TRAINING/BOOTCAMPS CERTIFICATIONS

- The Complete Web Developer in 2022; zero to Master Udemy.com
- Learn to build an e-commerce website using .NET and Angular Udemy.com
- Java Essentials, Spring Boot | React | AWS Amigoscode.com
- Azure DevOps, Docker, GitHub CI/CD, Jenkins youtube.com

### PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Godwin Portfolio (React, NodeJS, MySQL, Kubernetes, Docker, Docker-compose, AWS EC2, ECR, EKS) | View
- DOTNET E-Commerce Application (.NET Core, Angular, SQL, Azure, Redis, Docker, CI/CD) View
- Digital Restaurant Android application (Java, Android studio, SQLite, MVVC)
- React Application (React, Spring Boot, Docker)
- Diango Web Development Project (Diango)

### AWARDS AND LEADERSHIPS

- MSc Software Development, University of Glasgow, Glasgow
- Scrum Master, MSc IT Master Teams Project (Game development), 2021
- Won a PTDF Scholarship award to the UK, 2019/2020
- Best Graduating Student, Anglican secondary school, Makurdi, 2008
- Graduated with a first-class in Electrical and Electronics Eng. Federal University of Agriculture, Makurdi

## **EXPERIENCE**

# ❖ Full-Stack Developer – Jan 12, 2022 – Till date

## (Personal projects) University of Glasgow, Glasgow

- Designing and developing scalable and maintainable frontend components using React.js, Angular, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, font awesome, etc, and employing state management libraries like Redux for managing React application state.
- Building RESTful APIs and backend services using Node.js and Express.js, ASP.NET Core 7, Spring Boot, integrating with MySQL, PostgreSQL, or MongoDB to store and retrieve application data.
- Utilizing cloud services like AWS, Azure, Digital Ocean, Heroku, etc to deploy and manage applications, utilizing services like; Azure App Service, Azure SQL Database, EC2, EKS, ECR, Load balancers, etc., to build resilient, reliable and scalable cloud-based solutions.
- Leveraging Spring Boot and .NET technologies for building microservices, implementing JWT token-based authentication and authorization mechanisms for secure communication between services.
- Architecting and managing Kubernetes clusters on AWS EKS, streamlining deployment processes, and ensuring scalability and reliability of containerized applications.
- Automate build, test, and deployment pipelines using Jenkins and GitHub Actions, integrating with GitHub repositories to facilitate continuous integration and delivery of code.
- Implementing Docker-based containerization for applications, managing Docker images and registries to ensure
  efficient deployment and management of containerized environments.

# ❖ Software Developer – Jan 11, 2021 – Jan 11, 2022

# Software Development - University of Glasgow, Glasgow

- As the Scrum Master in a team, we utilize Agile Methodology to developer a reliable and efficient backend of a video game using java and suitable libraries.
- Developed projects using iteration plans to analyse, design, program and test applications before deadlines.
- Design and developed an android mobile application using Java in Android Studio and maintained good relationships between recycler views and adaptor classes using MVVC architectural design pattern.
- Recorded and save code on GitHub, use Trello software to create, save and exchange information like user stories. Debug and Troubleshoot errors on command line interface with the help of stackoverflow.com

# ❖ Java Developer - 2017 - 2021

## **Classic Computer Training Center, Oshun state**

- Collaborated closely with teams to develop and maintain robust software solutions, leveraging my expertise in Java programming and instructed the to save and backup their files on external version control tools like GitHub.
- Facilitated knowledge transfer by teaching Java courses, empowering others with the skills needed to excel in software development, and how to debug and troubleshoot errors from simple to complex.